Welcome to the demonstration lab
video.
For the small volume parenteral
where we will use powder for
reconstitution technique, the
compounder has performed hand
hygiene and garbing.
Please refer to the procedural
lab in the textbook for the step
by step procedure.
The compounder is going to tear
open the outer packaging of that
that 4 piggyback base hand
sanitize each time you come back
into the DCA and then we'll hang
that 4 piggy back on a hook on
the hang bar and set it to the
left.
We're going to place a sterile
isopropyl alcohol prep, bad the
diluent and another alcohol prep
pad.
We have our syringe and our
needle, and when we open our
sterile IPA swab, we want to
make sure that we're in the air
flow from the HEPA filter.
You'll tear open the packaging
and place that onto the DCA,
making sure that there's air
flow.
We'll take the cap off, we'll
open our second IPA swab and
we'll clean the port of the vial
and we will open the outer
packaging to our syringe.
You want to make sure that when
we expose the tip of the
syringe, it stays in the air
flow from the HEPA filter.
We'll open the packaging to our
needle.
We will recheck our connection
and then we want to activate the
syringe to loosen that plunger
and then we're going to pull
back the volume of the diluent
that we need.
We'll get into a dart, take the
cap off, come up and over the
vial.
You will be bevel up tippy toe,
invert that vial, get the needle
in liquid, and we'll start our
milking method.
We can troubleshoot the bubbles
before we get rid of all of the
air.
You'll want to by the barrel,
put your needle tip all the way
in, and then we'll use the work
surface here to clear those
bubbles.
And then you'll pull by the
barrel so that that needle is in
liquid and you'll push the rest
of the air that's in the syringe
into your vial.
We can change our hand position
so that we are going to use our
thumb and our middle finger on
the flat knob of the syringe.
And then with the forefinger
we'll pull the rest of the
volume that we need.
We'll come out of our vial and
then we'll tap slide and snap
our cap on, and we can put our
finger behind our graduation
marks to make sure that we have
the correct volume.
Now we'll prepare for the
ampicillin portion.
We'll get 2 new prep pads out.
And now we're going to use a
vented needle.
Specifically, we're going to use
a no core.
It's a little different than the
other vented needles.
We're going to open our first
sterile 70% IPA pad and put it
on the work surface, take the
cap off our ampicillin, open our
second IPA pad and then when
changing needles, needles first,
we're going to open the outer
packaging and we're going to
take our vented needle out.
You don't want to touch that
critical site now that it's out
of the packaging.
And then we're going to take off
our regular needle, turn the
wheel so that we are in the air
flow to place our vented needle.
We want to get into a dart, take
our cap up and over our vial.
Now here we're just going to go
in at 12:00 and 6:00 and then we
want to place that outer ring of
the no core into the stopper and
then we're going to lift
halfway.
We're going to push the rest of
our diluent into our vial and
we're going to come up and out.
You can swirl your vial, you
can, you can use your hand to
help reconstitute, you don't
want to hit the work surface.
It can scratch.
It can cause a dent in that
stainless steel work surface.
We'll get a new alcohol prep pad
for the cap, and then we need to
use a new sterile 70% prep pad
each time we go into that vial
tear.
That outer packaging, USP 797,
states that anytime we go back
into the vial, we must clean
with a new sterile 70% IPA pad.
We'll take the outer packaging
off our syringe, peel back the
packaging of our needle and
notice we have two critical
sites.
We want to make sure that we
don't touch contaminate.
We're going to get into a dart,
activate that syringe.
We don't need any air in this
syringe because we've done a
good job venting our small
volume parenteral ampicillin.
We'll take the cap off, you'll
be bevel up, we'll go into the
vial.
You wanna pull the needle into
the liquid and then you will
want to pull.
If you see a bubble, you can go
ahead and troubleshoot, Make
sure that that needle is all the
way into the vial and then we're
gonna push and we're going to
pull our dose.
If you don't have the pressure
that you need, we can
troubleshoot outside of the
vial.
You can go ahead and tap, slide,
snap your cap back on.
The first thing that we'll do is
we'll pull the plunger, We'll
tap that bubble, we'll pull the
plunger again, and then we're
going to use the Bunny method to
go ahead and trap the liquid
into your needle, the hub of
your needle, make sure that
there's no air.
And then we are going to open an
IPA prep swab.
We're going to clean the septum
of our vial.
Each time we go back in, we'll
get into a dart.
We'll take our cap off, come up
and over the vial.
You'll be bevel up and you'll
tippy toe to 12 and six.
You'll invert your vial and you
want your needle in liquid.
You're going to push push the
rest of what is in the hub and
the lumen and then you're going
to get into position and you're
going to pull the patient dose.
Then you'll hold on to the
barrel and you'll come out of
the vial.
You'll tap, slide and snap to
ensure that you have the correct
volume.
You can put your finger behind
to help you determine that you
have the correct volume.
We'll get another sterile IPA
prep swab and we're going to
clean the injection port.
You want to hold on to the
injection port with your left
hand, and then we're going to
use an overhand.
You want your syringe at 3:00
and 9:00.
You'll hold on to that injection
port, and then you'll just go
into that port without any
regard of whether the bevel is
up.
You'll just go straight in and
then you'll push your dose in by
the barrel.
You'll bring your syringe
straight out.
You'll tap, Slide, snap, and we
are finished.